Sean Woodward

Swiss Army Knife, Full Stack Developer

Taylorsville, UT 84123 seanwoodward@seanwoodwardweb.com 801-819-0525

My specialty is converting business need in to software. Most times companies will have some processes that started with an Excel file, then became an Access Database or SharePoint list and now needs a Web App, Reports, and probably some ETL processes as well. That is where I come in. I will understand the business need, the current state, the desired future state, and exceed at providing the desired result.

I have working experience with .NET Framework (MVC), .NET Core (MVC), Entity Framework (.NET and Core), SQL Server, SSRS, SSIS, and Console Service Applications. I have also recently been involved with a project that uses Blazor.

I have a Masters Degree in Computer Information Systems which I obtained from Independence University.

As well as working experience with the Microsoft suite of web development tools, I also use NodeJS for my own personal projects. In fact, my Portfolio / Blog is made using Next.js.

Willing to relocate to: Wisconsin - -

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Web Developer

SUTTER SHARED SERVICES - Salt Lake City, UT September 2018 to Present

As a Web Developer, I developed many applications for the contact center to support the tracking of many different workflows that were not easily captured within the CRM, or Telecom system. The most notable was an Employee Roster system that is still being used to track One on One interactions that supervisors have with their agents. This system has tracked over 23,700 One on One interactions between August 2019 and April 2021. We went from being unable to track the progress of One on One completions to 97.3% completions in the first month.

Knowledge Manager

SUTTER SHARED SERVICES - Salt Lake City, UT September 2014 to September 2018

As a knowledge manager I introduced Answer Path which was a COTS application to the system which 1600+ Contact Center agents interacted with every call, every day. Developed Custom JavaScript solutions to make the COTS application fit our needs.

Education

Master of Science in Computer Information Systems

Independence University - Salt Lake City, UT June 2015

Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems

Stevens-Henager College-Murray - Salt Lake City, UT November 2013

Skills

- .NET
- .NET Core
- MVC
- Microsoft SQL Server
- Entity Framework
- C#
- REST
- React
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- ASP.NET
- Web Services
- CSS
- APIs

Links

https://seanwoodwardweb.com

Awards

Distinguished Masters Thesis Award

2016

My Capstone Project / Masters Thesis was based on a project where I introduced AnswerPath as a new Knowledge Management system to the contact center.

My capstone Professor, and the Dean of the department were so impressed by it that they gave me an additional graduation award.

A copy of that Thesis may be download from my blog at https://seanwoodwardweb.com/blog/achievements-awards/distinguished-masters-thesis-award

Employee of the Month for September 2015

September 2015

I obtained an Employee of the Month Award in Steptember 2015 for maintaining and spreading the AnswerPath solution (referred to below as Interaction Workflow system) throughout the Contact Center system. I also had developed some Access Database Solutions before I had the appropriate Web Development tools on my computer, and before formally being transitioned to the team that handles those things. I also had ensured a smooth upgrade of our SharePoint system from 2007 to 2013.

The nomination which won me this award read as follows:

I would like to nominate Sean Woodward for EOM for September. Since joining the company one year ago, Sean has engineered a number of novel solutions to improve work at the PSC, including the development of custom tools and databases. His contributions include a tracking and reporting tool for the Transitions of Care and MPHS ED Discharge projects, the implementation of dynamic/ interactive workflows, an overhaul of the Master Roster, an Attendance Database, and a more indepth Improvement Log system. Most notably, he made the upgrade to SharePoint 2013 a seamless project for the PSC by developing a database to track the hundreds of pages requiring validation and producing daily reporting to keep leaders updated on his team's progress. He asked for permission to be in the building at 2:30am on Saturday to verify that all pages were working correctly, and the systems administrator overseeing the upgrade said that, "I've been through 7 of these migrations and I must say that this is by far the most prepared one I've seen." Sean has done more than maintain our SharePoint sites, much more than I ever anticipated could be done when he joined us 11 months ago, and I look forward to the many contributions he will make in the future.

COVID-19 Hotline Setup

April 2021

With the COVID-19 crisis the contact center needed to quickly respond to patient questions about COVID-19. By the time Vaccines were ready we also needed to assist people with making Vaccine appointments. My Role was to setup a SharePoint site where they could collaborate on information about over 100 vaccine locations and help direct agents to the correct places within the EHR system such that they could schedule an appointment for the patient at the right time, at the right location, for the right dose.

I also created a real-time outbound call back system where after a patients information was loaded a contact center agent could see it, assign themselves the item and call the patient back. Some of these patient lists exceeded 1000 patients.